{"tossups": [{"question": "This president\u2019s Secretary of the Treasury, William McAdoo, closed the New York Stock Exchange for months to keep foreign money in the U.S. despite the outbreak of war. A coded message to Mexico sent by Arthur Zimmerman led this man to break a promise of neutrality that had won this man re-election. For ten points, name this President of the United States who was unable to convince the U.S. Senate to join the League of Nations after World War I.", "answer": "Woodrow<b> Wilson</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "In 1999, this country and its eastern neighbor established \u201cEarthquake Diplomacy.\u201d This country\u2019s rapper Killah P was murdered by a supporter of the Golden Dawn Party. In 2015, there was high speculation that this country would abandon the Euro. For ten points, name this Balkan country, currently ruled by the SYRIZA Party under Alexis Tsipras, which has suffered from austerity and high unemployment in Athens.", "answer": "<b> Greece</b> (or<b> Hellenic Republic</b>)", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {}, {"question": "This leader appointed Ian MacGregor as head of the National Coal Board, which closed unprofitable mines, angering Arthur Scargill. This leader narrowly won a vote of no confidence to depose James Callaghan, and was succeeded by John Major after a cabinet minister resigned due to her combative style. This Prime Minister formed a friendship with Ronald Reagan and won the Falklands War. For ten points, name this Iron Lady, the first female Prime Minister of the United Kingdom.", "answer": "Margaret<b> Thatcher</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "For ten points, name this Argentine president and husband of Evita.", "answer": "Juan<b> Per\u00b4on</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "Early discoveries of this item in America occurred at the Reed farm in North Carolina, and Dahlongea, Georgia. In the aftermath of Executive Order 6102, the US built a storage facility for this item near Elizabethtown, Kentucky. The slogan \u201cPike\u2019s Peak or Bust!\u201d was used by people who traveled to Colorado to mine this material. For ten points, what precious metal is stored in bullion form at Fort Knox and was found, with silver, in the Comstock Lode?", "answer": "<b> gold</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "This city hosted Anthony Burns\u2019 fugitive slave trial. William Lloyd Garrison published his newspaper <em>The Liberator</em> from this city. An engraving by Paul Revere shows an attack led by Thomas Preston in this city; John Adams won the acquittal of the six attackers, who fired into a crowd, killing Crispus Attucks and four others. For ten points, name this New England city where British soldiers carried out a 1770\u201cmassacre.\u201d", "answer": "<b> Boston</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "A work about these people is divided into sections concerning \u201cHistory,\u201d \u201cPsychology,\u201d and \u201cBiology\u201dand argues that these people have become a passive \u201cOther.\u201d One philosopher distinguished these people from barbarians and the uneducated to argue for their suffrage. J.S. Mill wrote about the<em> Subjection of</em>, for ten points, name what group of people, the subjects of Simone Beauvoir\u2019s<em> The Second Sex</em>?", "answer": "<b> women</b> (accept equivalents)", "metadata": "Philosophy - Philosophy"}, {"question": "<em>Bolling v. Sharpe</em> repealed this doctrine at a federal level. It was initially ruled that this doctrine did not violate the Equal Protection Clause of the 14th Amendment, though Justice John Marshall Harlan dissented in the court case that established this doctrine,<em> Plessy v. Ferguson</em>. For ten points, name this doctrine that stated that segregation could occur, provided the conditions met a certain standard of fairness.", "answer": "<b> separate-but-equal</b> doctrine (prompt on segregation before mentioned)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "This novel\u2019s protagonist hopes that his barren and Ingsoc-obsessed wife, Katharine, will die so that he can marry a woman in the Junior Anti-Sex League. While working for Minitru, this novel\u2019s protagonist meets Julia, whom he later betrays in Room 101. The Tehran Conference inspired this novel\u2019s division of the world into the perpetually-warring Oceania, Eastasia, and Eurasia. For ten points, name this novel by George Orwell in which Winston Smith learns that Big Brother is always watching.", "answer": "<b> Nineteen Eighty-Four</b>", "metadata": "Literature - British Literature - Long Fiction"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "One ruler of this nation was advised by the Cientificos. One of this country\u2019s leaders was assassinated during the Ten Tragic Days. The Plan of Ayala called for land redistribution as a key component of this country\u2019s 1910 revolution, but revolutionary forces in this country continued to oppose Francisco Madero for not doing enough to help the poor. Porfirio Diaz was a dictator of, for ten points, what North American country where rebels were led by Emiliano Zapata and Pancho Villa?", "answer": "<b> Mexico</b> (or the United<b> Mexican</b> States)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "This ruler was forced to retreat through the Derbend Pass after his invasion of Sassanid Persia. This man\u2019s uncle Ruga united his people, then was succeeded by this man and his brother, Bleda. Aetius was forced to ally with Theodoric in order to defeat this ruler, who may have begun an invasion after Honoria sent him a ring. According to legend, this ruler died of a nosebleed. For ten points, name this \u201cScourge of God\u201d who attempted to sack Rome as the leader of the Huns.", "answer": "<b> Attila</b> the Hun", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {}, {"question": "An exterior part of this planet named for John Couch Adams has subdivisions called Fraternit\u00b4e, \u00b4Egalit\u00b4e, and Libert\u00b4e. In 1989, large storms on this planet were discovered by Voyager 2 and were named Scooter and the Great Dark Spot. Urbain Le Verrier was able to mathematically predict this planet\u2019s existence by studying the orbit of a neighbor planet. For ten points, name this planet with a methane-blue atmosphere that, after the demotion of Pluto, became the furthest planet of the Solar System.", "answer": "<b> Neptune</b>", "metadata": "Science - Other Science - Astronomy"}, {}, {"question": "<b>This battle\u2019s highest ranking English casualty was Edward, Duke of York. The Siege of</b> <b>Harfleur preceded this battle, whose losers raided an enemy (+)</b> <b>baggage train, causing</b> <b>the winning commander to order prisoner executions. One side in this battle drove sharp wooden stakes in front of their position; heavy rain then trapped (*)</b> Charles d\u2019Albret\u2019s cavalry in deep mud at the mercy of massed English longbows. For ten points, name this 1415 battle of the Hundred Years War, a victory for Henry V.", "answer": "Battle of<b> Agincourt</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b>Beyonce was criticized for insensitivity to this event in her track</b><em><b> XO</b></em><b>. This event delayed</b> <b>the State of the Union address by a week; instead, President (+)</b> <b>Reagan gave a speech</b> <b>from the Oval Office about a group who \u201c\u2019slipped the surly bonds of earth\u2019 to \u2018touch the face of God.\u2019\u201d An unusually large number of (*)</b> schoolchildren saw the broadcast of this event because Christa McAuliffe, a teacher, was aboard the doomed craft. For ten points, name this 1986 disaster in which a NASA shuttle disintegrated shortly after launch.", "answer": "Space Shuttle<b> Challenger</b> explosion", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>A musician attempted to avenge his friend\u2019s death by assassinating this ruler. In another incident, this man killed another would-be assassin who had hidden a dagger in a map. This</b> <b>man visited (+)</b> <b>Zhifu Island three times in attempts to gain immortality, but he died by</b> <b>swallowing mercury pills that were supposed to make him immortal. After his death, this leader was buried with (*)</b> thousands of terracotta warriors. For ten points, name this first emperor of the Qin dynasty and of a unified China.", "answer": "Qin<b> Shi Huang</b>di", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>A 2003 attempt to amend Article 23 of this region\u2019s law to allow police access to</b> <b>private property led to the downfall of its leader, Tung Chee-hwa. This region was the</b> <b>origin of the (+) H5N1 \u201cbird flu\u201d virus. The question of how to implement universal</b> <b>suffrage led to the Occupy Central movement in this region, in which protesting</b> <b>students carried (*)</b> umbrellas to defend against police. For ten points, name this former British colony which, along with Macau, became part of China in the 1990s.", "answer": "<b> Hong Kong</b> Special Administrative Region (or<b> Xianggang</b> Tebie Xingzhengqu)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}], "bonuses": []}